max@maxwillia.ms github.com/maxwilliams94

www.maxwillia.ms

Summary

Results-driven Python Engineer with 3+ years of experience delivering trading and operations software solutions. Managed full lifecycle of high-priority projects, from requirements analysis to production release. Scrum Master coordinating Agile processes for 7-member team, improving task completion rates and release date accuracy. Driver of improvements in testing and deployment automation and management of team infrastructure.

EXPERIENCE

Nomura International

London, UK

Associate Software Developer

Dec 2022 - Present

- Delivery of the full lifecycle, analysis to release, of prioritised projects with a range of scopes for features, solutions to functional weaknesses and firm-wide initiatives across the bank's global risk management platform.
- \circ Scrum master for a global team of 7 developers. Improved sprint task completion rates from below 50% to 75% and accuracy of proposed completion dates for implementation of features and fixes.
- Input into development of new CI/CD serverless/Kubernetes platform and its roll-out to the wider business as part of a working group.
- Pushed for, planned and executed a validation mapping engine rewrite as part of a prioritised project. Improved
 performance by 600%, with release of the new functionality supported by a suite of back-testing, integration and
 unit-testing functionality.
- Successful rewrite and re-platform of legacy automated trade rebooking process into containerised python from VBA. Improved performance by 30%, decreased production issues through robust error handling and increased observability through improvements to logging and reporting.
- Lead for creation of new trade validation library, incorporating automated unit-testing, CI/CD, rigorous coding standards within a robust software development lifecycle. Consideration for future compatibility as a dependency within a microservice architecture.

Wiley Edge (formerly mthree) — on-site at Nomura

London, UK

Python Engineer

July 2021 - Dec 2022

- Development, testing and release of robust processes and functionality focusing on data integrity, extensibility and testability.
- Support of the bank's risk management system through development of new features, bug fixes, refactoring/improvements, regulatory requirements and direct assistance to business users.
- Analysis, task creation, management and implementation of business-prioritised projects, requiring communication with business stakeholders and existing business knowledge.
- Developed a Linux-first proof of concept and productionised a process to replace a legacy VB6 application. Built
 out, prototyped and managed the team's first Linux infrastructure, contributing to the pipelines and supporting the
 architecture which underpins the wider business unit's containerisation processes.
- Pushed for and achieved early conversion to permanent employee within 18 months, requiring additional sign off and a cost to Nomura.

University of Bristol

Bristol, UK

Postgraduate Researcher/PhD Candidate

October 2017 - Mar 2022

- Design of algorithms and data structures for implementation of kinetic Monte Carlo model using FORTRAN08, translating scientific theory from different sources into mechanisms available to the model.
- Self-management and motivation during long sub-projects.
- Data analysis of model outputs, data plotting and statistical analysis using Python: Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Jupyter.
- Assisted students in design and troubleshooting of numerical simulations of physics concepts implemented in Python; marked and gave feedback on submitted code and formal reports.

Personal Projects

- 2018: IMPRESSION: Full-stack Online submission of molecules to machine-learning NMR shift prediction model.
- 2022: Gambit: Chess RESTful API to identify whether a chess game contains a recognised "gambit".

EDUCATION

University of Bristol

PhD, Computational Chemistry

Bristol, UK

Oct. 2017 - Mar. 2022

University of Warwick

MSc Diamond Science and Technology, 1st Class Honours

Coventry, UK

Oct. 2016 - Oct. 2017

University of Bristol

MSc Chemical Physics, 1st Class Honours

Bristol, UK

Oct. 2012 - Jul. 2016

Programming Skills

• Languages: Python, VBA

Technologies: Linux, Docker, Jenkins, Flask, Kubernetes, Git